<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Entity parent="template_unit_hero_cavalry_archer">
  <Auras>
    <Aura1>
      <Type>global</Type>
      <Affects>Structure</Affects>
      <Modifications>
        <Cost.BuildTime> <Multiply>0.75</Multiply> </Cost.BuildTime>
      </Modifications>
      <AuraName>Builder of the Land</AuraName>
      <AuraDescription>All buildings take 25% less time to construct during his lifetime.</AuraDescription>
    </Aura1>
    <Aura2>
      <Type>range</Type>
      <Radius>30</Radius>
      <Affects>CitizenSoldier</Affects>
      <Modifications>
        <Attack.Melee> <Multiply>1.1</Multiply> </Attack.Melee>
        <Attack.Hack> <Multiply>1.1</Multiply> </Attack.Hack>
        <Attack.Pierce> <Multiply>1.1</Multiply> </Attack.Pierce>
      </Modifications>
      <AuraName>Followers of His Majesty (Smsw Hm)</AuraName>
      <AuraDescription>Egyptian soldiers held their Pharaoh in awe, and hoped to gain his favour and reward by performing courageous exploits that would bring them to his attention. Increased attack for all citizen soldiers in the Pharaoh's hero aura.</AuraDescription>
    </Aura2>
  </Auras>
  <Builder>
    <Rate>1.0</Rate>
    <Entities datatype="tokens">
      structures/egyptian_sb_obelisk
    </Entities>
  </Builder>
  <Cost>
    <Population>2</Population>
  </Cost>
  <Identity>
    <Civ>egyptian</Civ>
    <GenericName>Thutmose I</GenericName>
    <SpecificName>Thutmose Akheperkare'</SpecificName>
    <Tooltip>"Builder of the Land"</Tooltip>
    <History>Thutmose I was a popular Pharaoh, a commoner by birth who had been a general of Ahmose, and he married into the royal family. Three of his offspring were Neferukheb, Hatshepsut, and Thutmose II. He engaged in a great deal of rebuilding, and commenced work on the Temple at Karnak. Early in his reign, Thutmose defeated the Nubians and established a vice-royalty in their land entitled the 'King's Son of Kush.' He also led campaigns east of Egypt to subdue some of the old foes that he and the Israelite monarchy had in common. One of these campaigns is recounted in I Kings 9:16: 'For Pharaoh king of Egypt had gone up, and taken Gezer, and burnt it with fire, and slain the Canaanites that dwelt in the city, and given it for a present unto his daughter, Solomon's wife.' This 'daughter of Pharaoh' who married Solomon (who had 'made affinity' with Pharaoh) was in all likelihood Neferukheb (or Nefrubity), who receded from Egyptian records thereafter.</History>
    <Icon>units/egyptian_hero_pharao.png</Icon>
    <RequiredTechnology>egyptian/phase_city_theban</RequiredTechnology>
  </Identity>
  <VisualActor>
    <Actor>units/egyptian/hero_pharao.xml</Actor>
  </VisualActor>
</Entity>
